Let's start by defining a database contract between our data and
our model. A contract is an agreement between our data model and our
views describing how information is stored. It will contain all the fields that
our user interface will display. Let's go into Android Studio to begin coding.
We'll add a new package to our project named data to encapsulate the data model.
Next, we'll create a contract class to store our column information.
The inner classes within our contract class will be used to define tables.
Each table will implement base columns because the columns represented by base
columns are useful. The ID column, in particular, must be part of our table
in order for our content provider integration to work later on in this lesson